<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>web on Blogging on Earth</title>
    <link>https://suncodeearth.github.io/blog/categories/web/</link>
    <description>Recent content in web on Blogging on Earth</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>sunsp.gis@gmail.com (Shipeng Sun)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>sunsp.gis@gmail.com (Shipeng Sun)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://suncodeearth.github.io/blog/categories/web/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Use your own domain name for GitHub Pages</title>
      <link>https://suncodeearth.github.io/blog/post/2025-07-10-use-your-own-domain-name-for-github-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>sunsp.gis@gmail.com (Shipeng Sun)</author>
      <guid>https://suncodeearth.github.io/blog/post/2025-07-10-use-your-own-domain-name-for-github-pages/</guid>
      <description>To point your own domain name like from GoDaddy and Webhostingpad to a GitHub Pages site, we need to use the A records in DNS settings. Specifically, we need to configure the DNS settings with own domain registrar (GoDaddy, Webhostingpad, etc.) and update your GitHub Pages settings. We&amp;rsquo;ll need to create A records, i.e., Address Records, pointing to the GitHub Pages IP addresses and verify the custom domain in GitHub. Here&amp;rsquo;s a step-by-step breakdown:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add SSL Certificate to IIS</title>
      <link>https://suncodeearth.github.io/blog/post/2025-02-25-add-ssl-certificate-to-iis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>sunsp.gis@gmail.com (Shipeng Sun)</author>
      <guid>https://suncodeearth.github.io/blog/post/2025-02-25-add-ssl-certificate-to-iis/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt  Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt is a free, automated, and open Certificate Authority (CA), run for the public&amp;rsquo;s benefit. We give people the digital certificates they need in order to enable HTTPS (SSL/TLS) for websites, for free, in the most user-friendly way we can.
 Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt Client ACME Clients help create certificates for the sites and get them validated through Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt.
Win-ACME win-acme is a good ACME client for Windows Server IIS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Develop Websites</title>
      <link>https://suncodeearth.github.io/blog/post/2024-09-28-develop-websites/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>sunsp.gis@gmail.com (Shipeng Sun)</author>
      <guid>https://suncodeearth.github.io/blog/post/2024-09-28-develop-websites/</guid>
      <description>Develop Websites using RWith RStudio and Quarto, there are quite a few options to develop simple but neat websites. From the RStudio, New Project, we can create Quarto Website, Bookdown, blogdown, and Simple R Markdown websites. Particularly for Quarto Website, all the interactive capabilities allowed by OJS could be incorporated.
The Quarto Website is based on a bootstrap template and has a simplistic appearance.
Importantly, Quarto or R markdown can directly hold DIV, which can be used by many JavaScript libraries to plot charts, maps, or tables.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
