<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Blogging on Earth</title>
    <link>https://suncodeearth.github.io/blog/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Blogging on Earth</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>sunsp.gis@gmail.com (Shipeng Sun)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>sunsp.gis@gmail.com (Shipeng Sun)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://suncodeearth.github.io/blog/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Add SSL Certificate to IIS</title>
      <link>https://suncodeearth.github.io/blog/post/2025-02-25-add-ssl-certificate-to-iis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>sunsp.gis@gmail.com (Shipeng Sun)</author>
      <guid>https://suncodeearth.github.io/blog/post/2025-02-25-add-ssl-certificate-to-iis/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt  Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt is a free, automated, and open Certificate Authority (CA), run for the public&amp;rsquo;s benefit. We give people the digital certificates they need in order to enable HTTPS (SSL/TLS) for websites, for free, in the most user-friendly way we can.
 Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt Client ACME Clients help create certificates for the sites and get them validated through Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt.
Win-ACME win-acme is a good ACME client for Windows Server IIS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Develop Websites</title>
      <link>https://suncodeearth.github.io/blog/post/2024-09-28-develop-websites/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>sunsp.gis@gmail.com (Shipeng Sun)</author>
      <guid>https://suncodeearth.github.io/blog/post/2024-09-28-develop-websites/</guid>
      <description>Develop Websites using R With RStudio and Quarto, there are quite a few options to develop simple but neat websites. From the RStudio, New Project, we can create Quarto Website, Bookdown, blogdown, and Simple R Markdown websites. Particularly for Quarto Website, all the interactive capabilities allowed by OJS could be incorporated.
The Quarto Website is based on a bootstrap template and has a simplistic appearance.
 Jekyll and Jekyll Themes Today, way more people are using Jekyll and pre-defined Jekyll Theme to develop websites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speeding up Python</title>
      <link>https://suncodeearth.github.io/blog/post/2024-06-15-speeding-up-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>sunsp.gis@gmail.com (Shipeng Sun)</author>
      <guid>https://suncodeearth.github.io/blog/post/2024-06-15-speeding-up-python/</guid>
      <description>Python, as an interpreted scripting language, is not characterized by speed or executive efficiency. A lot of utility tools like the package management tools, when written in Python, is not fast. Many tools have been rewritten using C/C++. Here are a few clues in terms of getting Python faster in many different aspects. This will be an on-going effort and updates will be published when there is new information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use census API in R and Python</title>
      <link>https://suncodeearth.github.io/blog/post/2024-06-13-use-census-api-in-r-and-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>sunsp.gis@gmail.com (Shipeng Sun)</author>
      <guid>https://suncodeearth.github.io/blog/post/2024-06-13-use-census-api-in-r-and-python/</guid>
      <description>Access Census data in Python Since Census publicized its data access API to developers, many Python pacakges had been developed to take advantage of that. Currently, there is a very long list of Python packages that allow use to access census data via scripts.
 census (work best with package us) censusdis (census discovery) cenpy census-data-downloader (for ACS data) pygris (for tiger boundary files)   Access Census data in R There are also many packages in R that facilitate census data accsess.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python on Mac OS</title>
      <link>https://suncodeearth.github.io/blog/post/2024-06-09-python-on-mac-os/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>sunsp.gis@gmail.com (Shipeng Sun)</author>
      <guid>https://suncodeearth.github.io/blog/post/2024-06-09-python-on-mac-os/</guid>
      <description>Set up Python on Mac OS Mamba forge package The best solution so far is to use MiniForge release. The Mamba Forge combination is the most efficient one. Download and run the Shell (.sh) installation file in Mac terminal. Use mamba init zsh to initialize Python for the terminal. zsh is the default shell for Mac OS. If a different shell is used, just change the parameter in mamba init.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>node.js management</title>
      <link>https://suncodeearth.github.io/blog/post/2024-06-08-node-js-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>sunsp.gis@gmail.com (Shipeng Sun)</author>
      <guid>https://suncodeearth.github.io/blog/post/2024-06-08-node-js-management/</guid>
      <description>Managing node.js Today most JavaScript libraries are developed, tested, and deployed or distributed via node.js framework. Many libraries stopped providing the regular js file for web developments. Instead, they are using modules, similar to Python. For legacy systems, a separate JS file is still needed and it is necessary to use node.js and npm to get the js file. This might be the only way to get the lasted version for some JS libraries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shortest Path in Polygons</title>
      <link>https://suncodeearth.github.io/blog/post/2023-03-18-shortest-path-in-polygons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>sunsp.gis@gmail.com (Shipeng Sun)</author>
      <guid>https://suncodeearth.github.io/blog/post/2023-03-18-shortest-path-in-polygons/</guid>
      <description>Finding the shortest path between two points within a (simple) polygon can be efficiently solved by using the funnel algorithm. For more details, see blog 1, blog 2, Paper 1 and Paper 2.
A good implementation in Python is available at GitHub margaeor</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Items in Action</title>
      <link>https://suncodeearth.github.io/blog/post/2022-11-29-items-in-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>sunsp.gis@gmail.com (Shipeng Sun)</author>
      <guid>https://suncodeearth.github.io/blog/post/2022-11-29-items-in-action/</guid>
      <description>This is an ongoing list of items in actions, aka list of TODO items. So often, some good directions that deserve serious investigations and explorations have to be put off. This blog is trying to make a record of these resources.
Open Geospatial DataWhite House Transparency and Open Government
Open data: an international comparison of strategies
Harvard CGA China Data Links
USGS Data Quality Assurance Best Practice and Examples</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS S3 CLI</title>
      <link>https://suncodeearth.github.io/blog/post/2022-10-27-aws-s3-cli/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>sunsp.gis@gmail.com (Shipeng Sun)</author>
      <guid>https://suncodeearth.github.io/blog/post/2022-10-27-aws-s3-cli/</guid>
      <description>AWS s3 (Simple Storage Service) is one of the simplest Amazon Web Service. It works just like a network drive. Amazon has granted many public institutions free S3 buckets. Smithsonian Institute (SI) is one of them. With its open access initiative, SI also shared a large amount of data on s3.
Smithsonian Open Access on github
AWS registry for Smithsonian
The data largely contain metadata at SI, 3D models, and pictures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Read New on new Reader</title>
      <link>https://suncodeearth.github.io/blog/post/setting-up-new-ebook-reader/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>sunsp.gis@gmail.com (Shipeng Sun)</author>
      <guid>https://suncodeearth.github.io/blog/post/setting-up-new-ebook-reader/</guid>
      <description>Acquired a new ebook reader Rakuten Kobo Elipsa. The device has a good size at 10 inch. It also supports Dropbox for loading books and OverDrive for borrowing from public libraries.
A few useful settings:
DoubleCommander: A open-source alternative to TotalCommander. A more powerful and more convenient file explorer.
Briss: A open source PDF cropper. It is running on Java. Windows removes Java by default, but many programs, like ArcGIS Pro, installed their own Java Running Environment (JRE).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PostgreSQL/PostGIS without instllation</title>
      <link>https://suncodeearth.github.io/blog/post/postgresql-start-cmd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>sunsp.gis@gmail.com (Shipeng Sun)</author>
      <guid>https://suncodeearth.github.io/blog/post/postgresql-start-cmd/</guid>
      <description>Using EnterpriseDB installer to install PostgreSQL and using Stackbuilder to install PostGIS is very easy. However, running PostgreSQL/PostGIS as a service, which is the default result of such installations, has some overhead because it is running in the background no matter it is actually used or not. Note that PostgreSQL has a small footprint when in “idle”. Nevertheless, it could be useful to run PostgreSQL/PostGIS as needed using binaries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regularly Report Computer IP with DHCP</title>
      <link>https://suncodeearth.github.io/blog/post/2022-05-26-regularly-report-computer-ip-with-dhcp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>sunsp.gis@gmail.com (Shipeng Sun)</author>
      <guid>https://suncodeearth.github.io/blog/post/2022-05-26-regularly-report-computer-ip-with-dhcp/</guid>
      <description>As many are working from home during/after the pandemic, it is super convenient and even necessary to remotely connected to office computers or home computers. However, wirelessly connected devices or ISP-connected devices may have their IP updated from time to time. This blog describes a short Python program that can automatically and periodically report a computer’s IP address. The information is saved into a text file, which can be saved in Dropbox or other cloud drives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Start bloggind using R blogdown</title>
      <link>https://suncodeearth.github.io/blog/post/2022-05-18-blogdown-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>sunsp.gis@gmail.com (Shipeng Sun)</author>
      <guid>https://suncodeearth.github.io/blog/post/2022-05-18-blogdown-start/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;How to start using R blogdown for effortless blogging.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vector Tiles for Leaflet</title>
      <link>https://suncodeearth.github.io/blog/post/vector-tiles-for-leaflet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>sunsp.gis@gmail.com (Shipeng Sun)</author>
      <guid>https://suncodeearth.github.io/blog/post/vector-tiles-for-leaflet/</guid>
      <description>Install GDAL ToolsThe GDAL tools are installed from https://www.gisinternals.com/. Install the core with Python applications, which contain some useful raster tools like gdal2tile.py.
Alternatively, it can be installed using OSGeo4W. However, OSGeo4W can interfere with PostgreSQL/PostGIS on GDAL for the setting. Therefore, it is not recommended to use OSGeo4W for GDAL.
As QGIS is part of OSGeo, it comes with GDAL pre-installed. So, it is also good to use the GDAL within QGIS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>https://suncodeearth.github.io/blog/post/2020-12-01-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>sunsp.gis@gmail.com (Shipeng Sun)</author>
      <guid>https://suncodeearth.github.io/blog/post/2020-12-01-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>R MarkdownThis is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars)## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.98 ## 3rd Qu.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
